We'll continue with the trend of addressing
我们将继续先解决
the prediction problem and reinforcement learning first.
强化学习中的预测问题
So, given a policy,
给定一个策略
how might we estimate its value function?
如何估算其值函数？
Let's build up how we did this in the previous lesson.
我们来回顾下在上节课是如何完成的
In our Monte Carlo approach,
在蒙特卡洛方法中
the agent interacted with the environment in episodes.
智能体以阶段形式与环境互动
After an episode finished,
一个阶段结束后
we looked at every state-action pair in the sequence.
我们按顺序查看每个状态动作对
If it was a first visit,
如果是首次经历
we calculated the corresponding return and used it to update the action value.
则计算相应的回报并使用它来更新动作值
And we did this for many, many episodes.
我们经历了很多很多个阶段
It's important to note that this algorithm is a solution for
需要注意的是 只要我们不在阶段之间更改策略
the prediction problem as long as we never change the policy between episodes.
该算法就可以解决预测问题
And as long as we run the algorithm for long enough,
只要我们运行该算法足够长的时间
we're guaranteed to end with a nice estimate for the action-value function.
就肯定能够获得一个很完美的动作值函数估计结果
But let's move our focus to this update step.
现在将重点转移到这个更新步骤
And there is an analogous equation if we instead want to keep track of the state values.
如果我们想要跟踪状态值 可以使用一个类似的方程式
Now for the rest of this video,
在本视频的剩余时间里
what we'll do is adapt this update step to come up with a new algorithm.
我们将修改该更新步骤并获得一个新的算法
Remember that the main idea behind this line is that the value of any state is
注意 这行的主要原理是任何状态的值
defined as the expected return that's likely to
定义为智能体遵守策略后
follow that state if the agent follows the policy.
在该状态之后很可能会出现的预期回报
So averaging sampled returns yields a good estimate.
对取样回报取平均值生成了很好的估值
At this point, I'll remind you of the Bellman expectation equation for the state values.
此刻 我要提醒下关于状态值的贝尔曼预期方程
It gives us a way to express the value of
它可以使用潜在地跟在后面的状态的值
any state in terms of the values of the states that could potentially follow.
表示任何状态的值
And so what if we used the equation just like the one above
如果我们使用像它上方的方程
it to motivate a slightly different update rule?
修改为一个稍微不同的更新规则呢？
So now instead of averaging sampled returns,
现在我们不再对取样回报取平均值
we average the sampled value of the sum of
而是对即时奖励的求和取样值
the immediate reward plus the discounted value of the next state.
加上下个状态的折扣值取平均值
And you'll notice that we now have an update step that
你将发现 现在的更新步骤
understands the value of a state in terms of the values of its successor states.
根据后续状态的值计算某个状态的值
And why would we want to do that anyway?
为何要这么做呢？
Well, the first thing to notice is that we've removed
首先要注意的是
any mention of the return that comes at the end of the episode.
我们删掉了阶段结束时的回报
And in fact, this new update step gives us
实际上 这个新的更新步骤
a way to update the state values after every time step.
使我们能够在每个时间步之后更新状态值
To see this, let's consider what would happen at an arbitrary time step t. As always,
为此 我们来看看在随机时间步 t 会发生什么
we'll use S_sub_t to denote the state.
和往常一样 我们将使用 St 表示状态
Say the agent uses the policy to pick its action A_sub_t,
假设智能体使用该策略选择动作
then it receives a reward and next state from the environment.
然后从环境那获得奖励和下个状态
So then what the prediction algorithm could do is use
然后 预测算法使用这个非常小的
this very small time window of information to update value function.
时间信息窗口更新值函数
Specifically, we'll update the value of this state at time t. In order to do that,
具体来说 我们将更新时间 t 的状态
we begin by looking up the values of the states from time t and time t plus one.
为此 首先我们查看时间 t 和 t+1 处状态的值
By also plugging in the reward,
通过代入奖励
we can calculate this entire right hand side,
我们能够计算整个右侧部分
and that's our new estimate for the value of the state at time t. Now it's
这就是在时间 t 时的状态的新估算值
important to realize that we won't have to wait
现在要注意的是 我们不用等待阶段结束
anymore until the end of the episode to update the values.
就能更新值
And this is the first algorithm you can use for
这是处理连续性任务时
the prediction problem when working with continuous tasks.
你可以使用的第一个预测问题算法
But before detailing the algorithm in full,
在详细讲解该算法之前
let's talk a bit more about what this update step accomplishes.
我们来讨论下这个更新步骤的作用
So at an arbitrary time step t,
在随机时间步 t
before the agent takes an action,
在智能体采取动作之前
it's best estimate for the value of
当前状态的最佳值估算
the current state is just what's contained in the value function.
包含在值函数中
But then once it takes an action and receives the reward and next state,
然后智能体采取动作并获得奖励和下个状态
well that's new information.
这是新的信息
And we can use it to express an alternative estimate for the value of the same state,
我们可以使用该信息表达同一状态的值替代估值
but in terms of the value of the state that followed.
不过采用的是后续状态的值
And we refer to this new estimate as the TD target.
将这个新的估值称为 TD 目标
So then what this entire update equation does is
这整个更新方程的作用
find some middle ground between the two estimates.
找到两个估值之间的中间值
You will set the value of alpha according to which estimate you trust more.
你将根据更加信任的估值设置 α 的值
To see this more clearly,
为了更清晰地体现这一点
we'll rewrite the updated equation.
我们将重写更新方程
Note that alpha must be set to a number between zero and one.
注意 α 必须设为 0 和 1 之间的某个数字
When alpha is set to one,
当 α 设为 1 时
the new estimate is just the TD target,
新的估值是 TD 目标
where we completely ignore and replace the previous estimate.
我们完全忽略并替换之前的估值
And if we were to set alpha to zero,
如果将 α 设为 0
we would completely ignore the target and keep the old estimate unchanged.
则完全忽略目标并保留旧的估值
This is not something that we'd ever want to do because then our agent would never learn.
我们肯定不希望出现这种结果 因为智能体将无法学到规律
But it will prove useful to set alpha to a small number that's close to zero.
但是将 α 设为一个接近 0 的小值很有帮助
And in general, the smaller alpha is,
通常 α 越小
the less we trust the target when performing an update,
我们在进行更新时对目标的信任就越低
and the more we rely on our existing estimate of the state value.
并且更加依赖于状态值的现有估值
You'll soon get a chance to experiment with setting the value of alpha yourself.
很快你将有机会自己设置该值
We'll now put this update step back into the context of the full algorithm,
现在将该更新步骤放入完整的算法中
which we'll call One-Step temporal difference or TD for short.
称之为一步时间差分 简称 TD
Of course the One-Step just refers to the fact that we
一步是指在每个时间步之后
update the value function after any individual step.
都更新值函数
You'll also see it referred to as TD zero.
它还称之为 TD(0)
The algorithm is designed to determine
该算法旨在确定
the state value function corresponding to a policy,
对应于某个策略的状态值函数
which we denote by pi.
我们将该策略表示为 π
We begin by initializing the value of each state to zero.
我们先将每个状态的值初始化为 0
Then, at every time step,
然后在每个时间步
the agent interacts with the environment,
智能体都与环境互动
choosing actions that are dictated by the policy.
选择由策略决定的动作
And immediately after receiving the reward and next state from the environment,
从环境中获得奖励和下个状态后
it updates the value function for the previous state.
它会立即更新上个状态的值函数
So this is the version for continuous tasks.
这就是连续性任务的版本
And as long as the agent interacts with the environment for long enough,
只要智能体与环境互动足够长的时间
the algorithm should return a nice estimate for the value function.
该算法就应该会返回一个很好的值函数逼近结果
Okay. And what about episodic tasks?
那么阶段性任务呢？
Well in that case,
如果是阶段性任务
we need only check at every time step if the most recent state is a terminal state.
我们只需检查在每个时间步 最近的状态是否为最终状态
And if so, we run the update step one last time to update the preceding state.
如果是 我们最后一次运行更新步骤以便更新上一个状态
Then, we start a new episode,
然后开始一个新的阶段
but as you can see the idea is basically the same.
原理基本是一样的